Matthew Spaulding

Software Engineering Leader

(727) 324-8369 mail@mattspaulding.org

PROFILE

I am a curious technologist with a Masters degree in Computer Science and over thirteen years of professional software engineering experience. I have a passion for leading people and helping others grow and succeed. Over the last six years, I have spent leading software engineering teams that have built world-class products using cutting-edge technologies. My focus is on coaching, mentoring, and thought leadership, driving best practices in software development and establishing the north star in technology vision.

EXPERIENCE

Spekit, Denver CO (Remote) — Software Engineering Manager

JAN 2022 - JULY 2022

- Empathetically led a brilliant team of engineers in a cross-functional multi-squad environment.
- Aligned squads with high-impact business goals and lead agile engineering practices while working closely with product and design.
- Coached engineers in their professional development to uncover growth opportunities and create a culture of continuous improvement.
- Regularly held 1:1 meetings with engineers and other leaders to uncover opportunities for growth.
- Interviewed and onboarded new engineers so they felt welcome and were able to hit the ground running.
- Peer reviewed engineer's technical contributions in a React/Python/PostgreSQL stack with Github pull requests.

PwC, Tampa FL (Remote) — *Software Engineering Manager*

MAR 2020 - NOV 2021

- Developed an enterprise cloud-based web application for a global accounting firm.
- Collaborated with business leaders to understand the business model, opportunities, and challenges.
- Provided technical direction and mentorship for engineers.
- Upheld a high standard code and design principles by leading code reviewing sessions.
- Utilized Azure DevOps ecosystem, creating work items, reviewing pull requests, and deployment pipelines.

SOCIAL PROFILES

MattSpaulding.org

Stack Overflow

Github

LeetCode

SKILLS

Reactis

Next.js

Angular

Typescript

Javascript

NgRx/RxJS

HTML

SCSS

Node

Mongo

Express

C#

Web API

.Net Core

Material Design

Bootstrap

NATIONALITY

US Citizen

LoanLogics, Jacksonville FL (Remote) — *Software Engineering Manager*

OCT 2018 - DEC 2019

- Developed v1.0 of enterprise cloud-based web application for leading mortgage loan underwriting company.
- Worked with stakeholders to determine scope of project and staffing needs to complete the project by the deadline.
- Hired and mentored a team of 15 developers.
- Developed Angular v8 applications using the latest design patterns, such as NgRx, and connected to a Java Web API.
- Implemented microservices architecture for better scaling of independent development teams and fault isolation in production.
- Deployed in AWS DevOps ecosystem using Jenkins to deliver docker containers to a cluster of Amazon EC2 instances.
- Tested code with Jasmine, Karma, and Cypress.

iProcedures, Tampa FL (Remote) — Tech Lead Software Engineer

MAR 2016 - OCT 2018

- Developed a cloud-based mobile Anesthesia Information Management System (AIMS).
- Developed a real-time vitals monitor using the D3.js charting library.
- Created Windows and Mac desktop applications using Electron.
- Automated versioning and deployment system to deliver updates to clients using Azure DevOps Services.
- Peer reviewed junior developers using the Gitflow workflow.

Toptal, San Francisco CA (Remote) — Software Engineer

SEPT 2015 - MAR 2016

The Learning Experience

- Created Bubble's U, a children's learning platform, for a nation-wide academy of early education.
- Developed in Angular v6 with custom UI components.
- link

Herndonwood Associates

- Created ReKoN, a risk management platform, for a banking institution.
- Developed in C#.Net using MVC pattern and JQuery Bootstrap frontend.
- Implemented Azure as the cloud server and storage solution.
- Created a multi-level role system.

Wolters Kluwer Law & Business, Tampa FL (Remote) — Software Engineer

JAN 2014 - SEPT 2015

- Developed MediRegs, a medical coding suite, for a global provider of technology solutions.
- Built a tool that uses fuzzy logic to find ICD10 codes.
- Built with C#.Net and Angular.js in the Azure cloud.

Mad Mobile, Tampa FL — Software Engineer

NOV 2012 - OCT 2013

- Built the Office Depot Windows Store app.
- Worked with the Office Depot development team to create a custom API.

AgileThought, Tampa FL — *Software Engineer*

AUG 2012 - NOV 2012

• Built custom software using C#.Net with knockout.js frontend.

Mad Mobile, Tampa FL — Software Engineer

DEC 2011 - AUG 2012

- Converted several eCommerce websites into mCommerce mobile websites.
- Scraped HTML from the websites and presented the data as JSON through a RESTful C#.Net Web API.

Enporion, Tampa FL — Junior Software Engineer

JAN 2011 - DEC 2011

- Developed an online reverse auction website for municipality utilities.
- Built with C#.Net MVC and Adobe Flex.

Raytheon, Largo FL — Junior Software Engineer

MAY 2009 - JULY 2010

- Developed software for a major U.S. Defense company.
- Developed a tool to automate calibration of electrical equipment in Basic. (Voltameter, oscilloscope, etc.)

EDUCATION

University of South Florida, Tampa FL *Master of Science in Computer Engineering*

2011

GPA: 3.25

Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society President

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Givvn

- Developed a tool for nonprofit organizations to build communities and collect donations.
- SaaS platform allows nonprofits to build websites and donation forms.
- Cloud CRM manages supporters and automatically sends emails to promote engagement.
- Built on the MERN stack (Mongo, Express, React, Node) with Next.js and served by Vercel.
- <u>link</u>